Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And we're bringing you the final lesson of our job interview series.
我们为你带来求职面试系列的最后一课。
That's right.
没错。
And in this lesson, we're going to be focusing on two very, very common, but sometimes difficult
在这一课中，我们将重点讨论两个非常非常常见，但有时又很难的
questions.
问题。
Okay, so we've talked about preparing for the job interview in part one.
好的，我们在第一部分已经讨论了如何准备求职面试。
Part two, we talked about educational background and work experience.
第二部分，我们讨论了教育背景和工作经验。
And in part three, what are we going to be looking at?
那么在第三部分，我们要看什么呢？
We're going to be looking at two questions, why we should hire you and your greatest weakness.
我们要看两个问题：为什么我们应该雇用你，以及你最大的弱点是什么。
Okay, so these are the classic common questions that you'll get at a job interview, right?
好的，这些都是求职面试中你会遇到的经典常见问题，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So why don't we just get started and we'll take a listen to the dialogue and see how
那我们直接开始，先听一下对话，看看
our interviewee handles these questions.
我们的面试者是如何处理这些问题的。
Very good.
很好。
Now, I have a couple of final questions.
现在，我有几个最后的问题。
I hope they're not too hard.
希望它们不会太难。
Well, why should we hire you?
嗯，为什么我们应该雇用你？
I think that I would be a perfect fit in this company.
我认为我会非常适合这家公司。
I have a unique combination of strong technical acumen with outstanding soft skills.
我拥有强大的技术敏锐度和出色的软技能的独特组合。
You know, I excel at building strong, long-term consumer relationships.
你知道，我擅长建立牢固、长期的客户关系。
For example, when I headed the customer support department in my previous company, our team
例如，当我在上一家公司领导客户支持部门时，我们的团队
resolved about 70% of our customers' problems.
解决了大约70%的客户问题。
I decided that we needed better information and technical preparation on our products.
我决定我们需要更好的产品信息和技术准备。
So after I implemented a series of training sessions in coordination with our technical
所以，在与技术部门协调实施了一系列培训课程后，
department, we were able to solve 90% of our customers' issues.
我们能够解决90%的客户问题。
Given the opportunity, I could bring this kind of success to this company.
如果有机会，我可以把这种成功带到这家公司。
Impressive.
令人印象深刻。
So, what would you consider to be your greatest weakness?
那么，你认为你最大的弱点是什么？
To be honest, I struggle with organization and time management.
老实说，我在组织能力和时间管理方面有困难。
Punctuality has never been a strength of mine.
守时从来不是我的强项。
I find it hard to organize my time effectively.
我发现很难有效地安排时间。
I've actually addressed this weakness recently by attending a workshop on efficient time
我最近通过参加一个关于高效时间管理的研讨会，
management.
实际上已经解决了这个弱点。
It helped me a lot by providing me with great insights on how to get organized and use my
它给了我很多关于如何组织起来和高效利用时间的深刻见解，
time efficiently.
对我帮助很大。
So, I think I'm getting better now.
所以，我觉得我现在正在变得更好。
Great.
很好。
Well, let me tell you that I am very pleased with this interview.
嗯，让我告诉你，我对这次面试非常满意。
We are shortlisting our candidates this week.
我们这周会筛选候选人。
And next week, we will inform our shortlisted candidates of the day and time for a second
下周，我们会通知入围的候选人
interview with our CEO.
与CEO进行第二次面试的日期和时间。
Great.
很好。
Thanks a lot.
非常感谢。
I hope to hear from you.
我希望能收到你的消息。
Goodbye.
再见。
Well, our interviewee is doing very well, but I think he had a little bit too many beans
嗯，我们的面试者表现得很好，但我觉得他可能吃了太多豆子
or chili.
或者辣椒。
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
Like, this is probably the most embarrassing thing I can think of.
这大概是我能想到的最尴尬的事了。
But he doesn't say anything.
但他什么也没说。
So, I don't know.
所以，我不知道。
Maybe he should have said, oh, pardon me, excuse me or something.
也许他应该说，哦，对不起，请原谅之类的。
I don't know.
我不知道。
It's a controversy.
这是个争议。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay.
好的。
But what isn't a controversy is the language because there's some great stuff in here.
但语言方面没有争议，因为这里面有一些很棒的内容。
All right.
好的。
Let's take a look at the language in Language Takeaway.
我们来看看“语言要点”中的语言。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
We've got some great phrases and words for you to use when you're talking about what
我们有一些很棒的短语和词汇，供你在谈论你能为公司带来
sort of benefits and skills and experience and expertise you can bring to a company.
什么样的好处、技能、经验和专长时使用。
Okay.
好的。
The first thing that he said, and it's a very interesting word, he said, technical acumen.
他说的第一件事，而且是一个非常有趣的词，他说的是“技术敏锐度”。
Technical acumen.
技术敏锐度。
Acumen.
敏锐度。
This is a really hard word.
这真是个难词。
What is acumen?
什么是敏锐度？
It's basically insight and understanding and the ability to make good and difficult decisions.
它基本上是指洞察力、理解力以及做出良好且困难决策的能力。
Okay.
好的。
So, he has a very strong technical acumen.
所以，他有很强的技术敏锐度。
So, a strong insight or understanding of technical issues.
也就是说，对技术问题有很强的洞察力或理解力。
Okay.
好的。
Or I can change it and may say, I have a very strong business acumen.
或者我可以改一下，说我有很强的商业敏锐度。
Exactly.
没错。
So, these are the two most common ways that this word is used, technical acumen, business
所以，这是这个词最常见的两种用法：技术敏锐度、商业
acumen.
敏锐度。
Okay.
好的。
Great.
很好。
Now, let's take a look at another word which is very interesting because everybody knows
现在，我们来看另一个词，这个词很有趣，因为每个人都
it.
知道它。
Yes.
是的。
Excel.
Excel。
Now, Excel is, of course, the software that you use, right?
现在，Excel当然是你使用的软件，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
But here, it's a verb meaning to be really, really good at something.
但在这里，它是一个动词，意思是“非常擅长某事”。
Right.
对。
To be the best maybe.
可能是“最擅长”。
Yeah.
是啊。
To excel at something.
擅长某事。
Yes.
是的。
So, I excel at cooking.
所以，我擅长烹饪。
All right.
好的。
So, Excel, you are the best.
所以，Excel，你是最棒的。
That's not really going to help me in a job interview, but the next word might.
这在求职面试中帮不了我，但下一个词可能可以。
Head.
领导。
Well, in the dialogue, we heard it as headed in the past, right?
嗯，在对话中，我们听到的是过去式“headed”，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
That's right.
没错。
He headed the customer support department.
他领导了客户支持部门。
So, I think this is a great word to use when you were saying, I was the leader.
所以，我认为这是一个很好的词，当你想说“我是领导者”时可以用。
I was the main person in charge.
我是主要负责人。
Yeah, the manager.
是的，经理。
So, this is a nice verb to use to show that you were leading something.
所以，这是一个很好的动词，用来表示你领导了某事。
Okay.
好的。
Now, for the next word.
现在，下一个词。
Struggle.
挣扎。
To struggle.
Struggle.
挣扎。
So, what does struggle mean?
那么，挣扎是什么意思？
It means that you have difficulty doing something.
意思是你在做某事时有困难。
So, it's hard for you.
所以，对你来说很难。
Yeah.
是啊。
For example, when I was in school, I struggled with math.
例如，我上学时，在数学方面很挣扎。
Okay.
好的。
And now, I struggle with Chinese.
现在，我在中文方面很挣扎。
Exactly.
没错。
So, to have a hard time.
所以，就是“有困难”。
Yeah.
是啊。
Why don't we hear a couple of examples of how this word is used?
我们听几个这个词用法的例子吧？
Example one.
例子一。
We're really struggling to reach our sales target.
我们真的在努力达到销售目标。
Example two.
例子二。
Yeah, to be honest, I do struggle with time management.
是啊，老实说，我在时间管理方面确实有困难。
Example three.
例子三。
The teacher farted in class and I really had to struggle not to laugh.
老师在课堂上放屁了，我真的很努力才忍住没笑。
Okay.
好的。
So, great examples.
很好的例子。
Let's move on to our next word.
我们继续下一个词。
Punctuality.
守时。
Okay.
好的。
So, to be punctual.
所以，“守时”的形容词形式。
It means to be on time, always.
意思是总是准时。
Always.
总是。
So, punctuality would be the noun form.
所以，“守时”是名词形式。
Right.
对。
So, the condition or the state of always being on time.
也就是总是准时的状态或情况。
Right.
对。
So, punctuality, to be punctual.
所以，守时，准时。
Yeah.
是啊。
And our interviewee struggles with punctuality.
我们的面试者在守时方面有困难。
Right.
对。
Like me.
就像我一样。
I guess you guys have something in common.
我猜你们有共同点。
We do.
确实有。
Now, he has a problem with punctuality, but he said he has addressed this weakness.
现在，他在守时方面有问题，但他说他已经解决了这个弱点。
Yes, to address.
是的，解决。
Address.
解决。
Now, if you notice, it's spelled the same way as address.
现在，如果你注意，它的拼写和“地址”一样。
That's right.
没错。
But you pronounce it differently.
但发音不同。
So, the verb address has the stress on the second syllable.
所以，动词“解决”的重音在第二个音节。
Okay.
好的。
Address.
解决。
Yes.
是的。
And that means to...
意思是……
Deal with.
处理。
To deal with the problem.
处理问题。
Yeah.
是啊。
To acknowledge the problem.
承认问题。
Yeah.
是啊。
And to try and solve it.
并试图解决它。
Okay.
好的。
So, different from your home address where you live.
所以，和你住的家庭地址不同。
Yeah.
是啊。
And there, the stress is on the first syllable.
那里重音在第一个音节。
Address.
地址。
Right.
对。
Perfect.
完美。
Very good.
很好。
Okay.
好的。
So, let's listen to this dialogue one more time, and then we'll come back and talk about
那么，我们再听一遍这段对话，然后回来讨论
these two questions.
这两个问题。
Greatest weakness and why should we hire you?
最大的弱点和为什么我们应该雇用你？
Very good.
很好。
So, I have a couple of final questions.
所以，我有几个最后的问题。
I hope they're not too hard.
希望它们不会太难。
Well, why should we hire you?
嗯，为什么我们应该雇用你？
I think that I would be a perfect fit in this company.
我认为我会非常适合这家公司。
I have a unique combination of strong technical acumen with outstanding soft skills.
我拥有强大的技术敏锐度和出色的软技能的独特组合。
I excel at building strong, long-term consumer relationships.
我擅长建立牢固、长期的客户关系。
For example, when I headed the customer support department in my previous company, our team
例如，当我在上一家公司领导客户支持部门时，我们的团队
resolved about 70% of our customers' problems.
解决了大约70%的客户问题。
I decided that we needed better information and technical preparation on our products.
我决定我们需要更好的产品信息和技术准备。
So after, I implemented a series of training sessions in coordination with our technical
所以在那之后，我协调技术部门实施了一系列培训课程。
department.
部门。
We were able to solve 90% of our customers' issues.
我们成功解决了90%的客户问题。
Given the opportunity, I could bring this kind of success to this company.
如果有机会，我能把这种成功带到这家公司。
Impressive.
令人印象深刻。
So, what would you consider to be your greatest weakness?
那么，你认为自己最大的弱点是什么？
To be honest, I struggle with organization and time management.
老实说，我在组织能力和时间管理方面有些困难。
Punctuality has never been a strength of mine.
守时从来不是我的强项。
I find it hard to organize my time effectively.
我发现很难有效地安排时间。
I've actually addressed this weakness recently by attending a workshop on efficient time
我最近通过参加一个高效时间管理研讨会来应对这个弱点，
management.
管理。
It helped me a lot by providing me with great insights on how to get organized and use my
它给了我很多关于如何有条理地利用时间的宝贵见解，帮了我大忙，
time efficiently.
高效地利用时间。
So, I think I'm getting better now.
所以，我觉得我现在正在进步。
Great.
很好。
Well, let me tell you that I am very pleased with this interview.
嗯，我得说我对这次面试非常满意。
We are shortlisting our candidates this week.
我们这周会筛选候选人。
And next week, we will inform our shortlisted candidates of the day and time for a second
下周，我们会通知入围的候选人第二轮面试的日期和时间，
interview with our CEO.
与我们的CEO进行面试。
Great.
太好了。
Thanks a lot.
非常感谢。
I hope to hear from you.
希望能收到您的消息。
Goodbye.
再见。
All right, Marco.
好的，Marco。
Well, this classic question, why should we hire you?
嗯，这个经典问题，“我们为什么要雇用你？”
I think you'll hear it in many, many different interviews.
我想你会在很多很多不同的面试中听到它。
And how did he deal with it here?
他在这里是怎么处理的呢？
Well, the first thing that he said is very, very important because they're asking you
嗯，他说的第一件事非常重要，因为他们问你“为什么”，
why so your immediate reaction would be to answer with because or I think that.
你下意识的反应可能会用“因为”或“我认为”来回答。
But there's a different way of approaching it, which is a little bit more professional.
但有一种不同的处理方式，更专业一些。
He said, I think that I would be a perfect fit in this company.
他说：“我认为我会非常适合这家公司。”
I think I would be a perfect fit in this company.
我认为我会非常适合这家公司。
That's how he started his answer.
他就是这么开始回答的。
And then he explained why.
然后他解释了原因。
So this sounds really strong, doesn't it?
这听起来很有力，不是吗？
Yeah, basically, it just makes you seem to be very confident and puts you like you are
是的，基本上，这让你显得非常自信，并且让你感觉像是
already part of the company.
已经是公司的一员了。
So this is a great way to start off this question.
所以这是回答这个问题的好开头。
But you got to follow this up with some information.
但你得接着提供一些信息。
So what kind of information should you be giving?
那么你应该提供什么样的信息呢？
Well, like we talked about in your work experience, the same thing goes here.
嗯，就像我们之前谈到的关于工作经验一样，这里也一样。
What do you have to offer to this company?
你能为这家公司提供什么？
What special skills or insights or experience can you bring that would help us?
你能带来什么特殊的技能、见解或经验来帮助我们？
Yeah, that nobody else can bring.
是的，别人带不来的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
So again, you have to start talking about your strengths and your previous experience,
所以，你又要开始谈论你的优势和过往经验，
but with examples, right?
但要举例子，对吧？
Very, very specific examples.
非常非常具体的例子。
And whenever you can throw in some numbers or some specific successes that you have had.
并且尽可能加入一些数字或你取得的具体成功。
Exactly.
没错。
And once you've talked about these things, you can close off this answer by saying, given
一旦你谈完了这些，你可以用这句话来结束回答：“如果有机会，
the opportunity, I could bring this kind of success to this company.
我能把这种成功带到这家公司。”
Given the opportunity, I could bring this kind of success to this company.
如果有机会，我能把这种成功带到这家公司。
So that is just like a magical sentence saying like, if you give me the chance, I will demonstrate
这就像一句神奇的句子，意思是：如果你给我机会，我会展示
how good I am and how I can help this company.
我有多优秀，以及我如何能帮助这家公司。
Yes.
是的。
A really, really strong closing argument.
一个非常非常有力的结束语。
Yes.
是的。
So that's the way you should more or less approach that question, right?
所以，这大致就是你处理那个问题的方式，对吧？
All right, but let's turn now to the classic, classic question.
好的，现在我们来看看那个经典中的经典问题。
Your greatest weakness.
你最大的弱点。
What is your greatest weakness?
你最大的弱点是什么？
When you get this question, be sure to not say, my greatest weakness is I work too much.
当你遇到这个问题时，千万不要说：“我最大的弱点是我工作太努力了。”
My greatest weakness is I'm a workaholic.
我最大的弱点是我是一个工作狂。
Right.
对。
Or what was it?
或者是什么来着？
Oh, or I am a perfectionist.
哦，或者“我是个完美主义者”。
Yeah, these we can see right through these.
是的，这些我们一眼就能看穿。
I mean, they're too obvious and they're too, they're too silly.
我的意思是，它们太明显了，也太傻了。
I mean, everyone has a weakness, so don't try and turn it around into a strength.
我是说，每个人都有弱点，所以不要试图把它变成优点。
I just don't think that's a good idea.
我只是觉得那不是个好主意。
Okay.
好的。
So yeah, be sure to stay away from these answers, but you can say anything.
所以，一定要避开这些答案，但你可以说任何东西。
Like in this case, he has a problem with being on time.
比如在这个例子里，他准时方面有问题。
Yeah.
是的。
So be honest, say what one of your greatest weaknesses are.
所以要诚实，说出你最大的弱点之一是什么。
But the key to making this weakness look good is saying what you are doing to solve this
但让这个弱点看起来不错的关键是，说出你正在做什么来解决
weakness.
这个弱点。
Exactly.
没错。
So really be truthful.
所以要真正地诚实。
Tell the interviewer what you're not good at because there's obviously something that
告诉面试官你不擅长什么，因为显然有些事情
you're not good at.
你是不擅长的。
Exactly.
没错。
So you can say, I am usually late, but I am getting more organized.
所以你可以说：“我通常迟到，但我正在变得更有条理。”
I am doing the seminar.
我正在参加研讨会。
Let the interviewer know that you are trying to improve this weakness.
让面试官知道你正在努力改进这个弱点。
Exactly.
没错。
And be sure to also think about your strength, right?
同时也要考虑你的优势，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Be prepared to answer the question, what is your greatest strength?
准备好回答“你最大的优势是什么？”这个问题。
So and again, when you're talking about your strengths, be sure it's something more specific
所以，同样，当你谈论你的优势时，一定要比说
than saying, oh, I'm very responsible.
“哦，我很负责任”更具体。
Yeah.
是的。
You want to be as specific as you can.
你要尽可能具体。
And again, give those examples, give those successes, give those numbers.
并且再次，给出那些例子，给出那些成功，给出那些数字。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
So think about your weaknesses.
所以，想想你的弱点。
Think about your strengths.
想想你的优势。
If you don't know them, ask people, ask your colleagues or ask your friends, what do you
如果你不知道，问问别人，问问你的同事或朋友：“你觉得
think is my greatest strength?
我最大的优势是什么？”
Maybe you're a funny person.
也许你是个有趣的人。
That's a strength.
那是一个优势。
Yes.
是的。
Well, remember there are three parts to this interviewing series and you can find them
嗯，记住这个面试系列有三个部分，你可以在我们的网站上找到它们，
on our website at EnglishPod.com.
网址是EnglishPod.com。
Right.
对。
Come to our website EnglishPod.com.
来我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
You can look at all of these three lessons and I hope they are really helpful.
你可以看看这三节课，希望它们对你有帮助。
And of course, if you have any questions or comments or maybe you'd like a little bit
当然，如果你有任何问题、评论，或者你希望这个面试系列
more of this interview series, let us know.
再多一些内容，请告诉我们。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
Well, thanks for listening.
嗯，感谢收听。
Good luck in your interviews and until next time.
祝你们面试顺利，下次再见。
Goodbye.
再见。
Cheers.
干杯。